Say that we have our predicted state x described by a Gaussian distribution.
假设我们使用高斯分布描述了预测状态 x
If we map this Gaussian to a nonlinear function h,
如果我们把这个高斯分布映射到非线性函数 h
then the result is not a Gaussian distribution anymore.
结果就不再是高斯分布了
So the Kalman filter is not applicable anymore.
因此 卡尔曼滤波器也不再适用
And in order to visualize the impact of this nonlinear transformation,
为了可视化这个非线性转换的影响
I've created a simple test.
我创建了一个简单的测试
I've generated a list of 10,000 random values drawn from
我生成了一个包括 1 万个随机值的列表
a normal distribution with a mean of 0 and a standard deviation of 3.
这些值取自正态分布 均值为 0 标准差为 3
And here is the histogram of these values.
这是这些值的直方图
And you can see that it follows a Gaussian shape.
你可以看到 它的形状符合高斯分布
Then for each of these values xi, I have computed the corresponding h over xi.
对于每个值 xi 我计算了对应的 h
And in my case, h is the arctangent of xi, which
在本例中 h 是 xi 的反正切
is a nonlinear function that is also used in our radar measurement model.
它是一个非线性函数 在我们的雷达测量模型中也用到了
The result is stored in an output list.
结果存储在一个输出列表中
And finally, I use my output list to generate a new histogram.
最后 我使用我们的输出列表 生成了一个新的直方图
What we see here is that the resulting distribution is not a Gaussian any more,
这里我们可以看到 对应的分布不再是高斯分布
because of the nonlinearity of h.
原因是 h 是非线性的
Moreover, the transformed density cannot be represented in closed form.
此转换后的密度不能以闭型表示
So Kalman filter update equations are not applicable here.
因此 这里也不使用卡尔曼更新方程
How can we fix that?
怎么解决这个问题呢？
A possible solution is to linearize the h(x) function.
一个可行方案是 对 h(x) 函数进行线性化操作
And that's the key idea of the so-called extended Kalman filter.
这也是扩展卡尔曼滤波器的核心思想
So we have to approximate our measurement function h by a linear
因此 我们必须使用在原始高斯分布的均值位置
function which is tangent to h at the mean location of the original Gaussian.
和 h 相切的一个线性函数 近似出测量值函数
So I repeated the same test.
我重复了同样的小测试
I used the same list of randomly sampled values from a normal distribution.
我使用了正态分布的同一个随机抽样值列表
But instead of applying the nonlinear function h,
但我没有应用非线性函数 h
all the xi values were passed through the linear approximation of h.
而是通过 h 的线性近似传递所有 xi 值
And we can see now that unlike the non linear case, this time,
我们现在可以看到 和非线性案例不同的是
our resulting distribution retained the Gaussian nature.
这一次 我们的分布结果保持了高斯分布的特征
So how do we linearize a nonlinear function?
那么 如何对非线性函数进行线性化处理呢？
The extended Kalman filter uses a method called first order Taylor expansion.
扩展卡尔曼滤波器使用了一阶泰勒展开法
So what we do is we first evaluate the nonlinear function h at the mean
我们首先评估在均值位置 μ 的非线性函数
location mu, which is the best estimate of our predicted distribution.
这也是预测分布的最佳估算
And then we extrapolate the line with slope around mu.
然后 我们使用围绕 μ 的斜度来推断这条线
And this slope is given by the first derivative of h.
斜率由 h 的第一个导数给出
Similarly, extended Kalman filters implement exactly the same linearization
类似地 当状态转换 f(x) 也是非线性时
when the state transition f of x is also nonlinear.
扩展卡尔曼滤波器会进行完全一样的线性化转换
So in the next quiz, I would like
在接下来的练习中 我希望你能
you to compute as a practice the linear equation for a given function.
计算一个给定函数的线性方程